Guide to the Janet Hamill archive, 1967-2010.
Hamill, Janet archive,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Janet Hamill archive, 1967-2010.
8062
Hamill, Janet.
12 cubic feet.
Correspondence, photographs, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Janet Hamill Archive contains extensive materials that document the life and work of Janet Hamill and illuminates Hamill's unique relationship with her longtime friend Patti Smith.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Poet, performer and artist.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Janet Hamill Archive contains extensive materials that document the life and work of Janet Hamill. The archive additionally illuminates Hamill's unique relationship with her longtime friend, poet, writer, singer-songwriter and artist Patti Smith. Included are correspondence (approximately 380 letters), manuscripts, journals, notebooks, diaries (several thousand pages dated 1967-2007) and photographs documenting Hamill's work. Also included are materials pertaining to Patti Smith consisting of correspondence (approximately 100 letters), manuscripts and notes concerning the book Just Kids (approximately 1,000 pages) and photographs of and by Patti Smith.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hamill, Janet.; Hamill, Janet.; Smith, Patti.; Smith, Patti.; Smith, Patti.
Subjects:
Artists, American -- New York (State) -- New York.; Poets, American -- New York (State) -- New York.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I: Correspondence
Subseries Ia: General Correspondence
Subseries Ib: Publishing Correspondence
Subseries Ic: Miscellaneous Correspondence
Series II: Writings by Janet Hamill
Series III: Announcements for Performances/Readings and Related Material
Series IV: Photographs
Series V: Audio and Visual Items
Series VI: Journals, Diaries and Notebooks
Series VII: Moving Star
Series VIII: Personal Effects and Miscellaneous Items
Series IX: Artwork by Others
Series X: Patti Smith
Subseries Xa: Correspondence with Janet Hamill
Subseries Xb: Photographs of Patti Smith
Subseries Xc: Artwork by Patti Smith Subseries Xd: Just Kids Manuscripts and Notes
Subseries Xe: Assorted Materials
Subseries Xf: Robert Mapplethorpe Subseries Xg: Performances and Events with Patti Smith and Janet Hamill
Subseries Xh: Audio Materials
Subseries Xi: Posters and Broadsides
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Subseries Ia: General Correspondence
    - A (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 3 TL (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Includes 1 donation envelope; 1 information pamphlet; 1 free gift flyer; 1 addressed and stamped return envelope.
    - Amram, David, November 2, 2002-October 5, 2006; 4 EM, 2 Newspaper (Box 1, Folder 2)
      American composer, musician, conductor, and writer. Amram has composed more than 100 orchestral and chamber music works, and written many scores for Broadway theater and film, including Robert Frank and Alfred Leslie’s Pull My Daisy.
    - Anderson, Craig, March 8, 1986-March 19, 2002; 7 ACS, 6 APCS, 1 TL (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Anderson is the manager of the Strand Rare Book Room. He is the stepson of American playwright Maxwell Anderson
    - Auster, Paul, March 16, 1987-September 8, 1990; 2 ALS (Box 1, Folder 4)
      American author. Auster has published poems, essays, novels of his own as well as translations of French writers.
    - B (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 3 ALS, 1 EM (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Baron, Richard, October 24, 1982-May 2, 1991; 1 ALS, 2 APCS, 3 TLS (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Baron is a photographer and collaborated on a book with Janet Hamill.
    - Benedict, Dorothy, July 15, 1992-April 5, 1995; 1 ALS, 2 APCS (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bertei, Adele, September 26, 1998-December 17, 2000; 5 ACS, 1 APCS, 4 EM, 1 TL, 2 TLS (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Musician and performer, best known for being a member of the seminal New York No Wave band The Contortions and part of the early all-girl band The Bloods. Had roles in many New York Underground films and is also known for her work as a backup singer. She and Janet are longtime friends and performed together in the past
    - Blagg, Max, January 9, 1979-April 5, 1990; 2 Events, 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Poet and performer, he and Janet had numerous readings together
    - BOMB Magazine, January 31, 1986-May 1, 1991; 1 AL, 3 ALS, 2 TLS (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - C (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 ACS, 1 ALS, 1 APCS, 3 TLS (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Cafe Review, The, September 28, 1993-November 16, 1995; 2 ALS, 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Carb, Nathan, October 27, 2005; 1 ACS, 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Former Janet English professor and chair of English Department at Rowan University.
    - Carter, Charlotte, February 29, 1988; 1 APCS (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Caruso, Joseph, March 4, 1993-March 3, 1995; 2 ALS (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Chalifoux, Kristine, December 15, 1988-November 20, 1989; 1 ALS, 1 APSC (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Cherry, Amy, May 25, 1995-August 18, 2000; 1 EM, 2 TLS (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Cherry was the editor at Norton for the never realized Eternal Café, a collaboration between Janet and Paula Smith
    - Chester, Laura, April 30, 1987-December 2, 1991; 10 TLS (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Writer, editor, poet.
    - City Lights Booksellers and Publishers, March 13, 1988-November 3, 2005; 5 TLS (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Codrescu, Andrei, March 19, 1987; 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Colon, Frank, June 28-July 10, 1996; 2 ACS (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Colorado North Review, October 4-24, 1990; 1 ALS, 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Contact II, September 7, 1981-July 29, 1982; 3 TLS (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Cuyler, Susanna, January 8, 1985-May 10, 1995; 2 APCS, 2 ALS, 9 TLS, 1 TPCS (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Cress, Cathy, January 25, 1980-March 4, 2006; 10 ACS, 2 APCS, 9 ALS, 38 TLS (Box 1, Folder 25-27)
      Cathy Cress attended Glassboro State College with Janet and was the editor of the college newspaper. She has an MSW in aging and is an expert on geriatric care.
    - Csida, Joe and June Bundy, January 15, 1981-August 6, 2004; 8 ACS, 14 TLS (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Csida, Joe, 1984-1987; 11 ACS (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - DeRugeris, CK, September 2, 1977-January 30, 1999; 3 ACS, 18 ALS, 5 MS, 39 TLS (Box 1, Folder 30-32)
      DeRugeris attended Glassboro State College with Janet. He is a poet and author of speculative fiction
    - Dun and Bradstreet, August 27, 1980-May 10, 1986; 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Includes photocopy of article by Janet's father
    - E (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Educational Alliance, The, December 4, 2002-March 5, 2003; 8 Event, 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Ehrman, Sally, July 7, 1982-June 24, 1987; 1 ACS, 1 ALS, 1 APCS (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Equator Books, August 29, 1980-April 27, 1990; 4 Events (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - F (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 ALS, 1 APSC (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Foye, Raymond, April 28, 1993; 1 APCS (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Hanuman Books publisher.
    - G (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 TLS, 2 ACS, 1 APCS (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Grad, Wendy, June 16, 1980; 1 Event, 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - H (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Hamill, Bryan, February 14, 2006; 1 ALS, 1 EM (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Hamill, Janet, February 14, 1987-September 1, 2004; 9 ACS, 1 EM, 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Janet's sister-in-law.
    - Hamill, Judy, Date unknown; 2 ACS (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Janet's sister.
    - Hamill, Trid, October 29, 1988; 7 ACS, 1 ALS, 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Holman, Bob, July 4, 1982-February 18, 2003; 3 ALS, 5 APCS, 6 EM, 1 event, 1 MS, 2 TLS (Box 1, Folder 47)
      Holman was instrumental in the reopening of the Nuyorican Poets Café and founded the Bowery Poetry Club.
    - Howe, Fanny, April 28, 1996; 1 APCS (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Hudson, Patti, August 30, 1995-December 9, 2005; 4 ALS, 1 EM, 2 event (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Photographer and artist. Hudson is a longtime friend of both Patti Smith and Janet.
    - I (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 8 event, 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Indiana, Gary, September 24, 1993; 1 ACS (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - J (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 ALS, 1 TL (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Junes, P., November 2, 2004-February 13, 2006; 2 ACS (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - K (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Kozik, Adam, October 1, 2004-February 7, 2005; 2 ACS (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Konglomerati Press, March 27, 1980-February 17, 1983; 7 TLS (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Kraman, Cynthia, May 25, 1987-July 19, 1998; 3 ACS, 8 ALS, 14 APCS, 2 MS, 2 TLS, 1 Photo (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Kruger, Barbara, Date unknown; 1 Event (Box 1, Folder 58)
      Barbara Kruger is a well-known conceptual artist and was friends with JH throughout the 70’s. They were introduced to each other by Ken Tisa.
    - L (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 Newsletter, 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Lance, Jeanne, March 20, 1989-July 17, 1993; 3 ALS, 3 APCS (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Lewis, Sandy and Joel, 2002; 1 ACS (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Library of Congress, December 5, 1975; 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Linn, Judy, October 10, 1987-November 30, 1993; 3 Event (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Long Shot Productions, July 15, 1998-August 9, 1998; 1 TLS, 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - M (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 ACS, 1 ALS, 2 TLS (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Mechem, James, July 7, 1988-January 18, 1989; 3 APCS (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Morrissey, Mike, Date unknown; 4 ACS, 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 67)
      Including cards.
    - Muraskiewicz, Gregory, November 11, 1985-March 3, 1986; 1 ACS, 2 APCS (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - N (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 ACS, 1 Card, 3 TLS, MS (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, December 18, 2000; 2 TLS (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - New Wilderness Foundation Inc., The, August 13, 1980-August 12, 1981; 2 ALS, 1 MS, 1 Pamphlet, 1 Pen, 3 TLS (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - O (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 2 ACS, 1 Event, 2 Invoices (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Okulski, Gloryia, January 15, 1990-August 24, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Gloryia Okulski was an inspirational English teacher during JH’s junior year of high school. Janet considers her responsible for her being a poet
    - Orange County Community College, May 31, 1991-August 10, 1999; 2 ALS, 3 TLS, 1 transcript, 1 EM (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Orr, Denie, August 26, 1985-December 26, 1992; 1 ACS, 1 ALS, 2 APCS, 2 TCS, 2 TLS (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Owen, Maureen, November 13, 1979-September 22, 2004; 4 ACS, 12 APCS, 1 EM, 4 ALS, 1 fax, 8 TLS (Box 2, Folder 5)
      American poet, publisher and editor. Owen was co-director of the St. Mark’s Poetry Project in New York City. She is the editor and publisher of Telephone Books and has published two of JH’s books.
    - P (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 2 ACS, 2 ALS, 2 TLS (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Padgett, Ron, March 12-July 8, 1987; 1 APCS, 1 TLS (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Peabody, Richard, February 4, 1998-June 30, 2004; 1 APCS, 1 ALS, 3 TLS, MS, Event (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Perlman, John, May 16-23, 1974; 2 ALS (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Poetry Project, The, November 13, 1978-January 25, 2005; 5 ALS, 2 Event, 13 TLS, MS, 3 Newsletters (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Poets and Writers, Inc., December 13, 1989-April 2, 1901; 1 ACS, 1 Event, 1 TL, 1 TLS (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Poets House, February 4, 1988-September 7, 1993; 1 TLS, 3 papers (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - R (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 2 ALS, 1 event (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Rothenberg, Jerome, August 16, 1979-March 27, 1990; 2 APCS (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Rowan University, April 14, 2001-April 8, 2006; 15 EM, 2 TLS (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Rowoholt, January 1, 1982-April 20, 1983; 1 Event, 2 ALS, 1 ALS, 1 Contract, 1 Invoice (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - S (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 3 ACS, 2 EM, 1 TLS (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Schneider, Gail, December 18, 1995; 1 ACS, 1 APCS (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Singh, Ravi, January 10, 1986-January 7, 1989; 1 Event, 1 MS, 1 printout (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Includes "The New Romantics--A Manifesto."
    - Stablein, Marilyn, May 19, 1999-June 25, 1999; 1 ACS, 1 TLS (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Tart, Indrek, August 8, 1990-May 8, 1991; 1 ACS, 3 TLS, MS, Postcards (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Tisa, Ken, 1980; 1 APCS (Box 2, Folder 22)
      An artist and early friend of Janet and Patti Smith. He has also collaborated with poets Max Blagg and Kenward Elmslie.
    - Torsello, Bob, March 6, 2002-November 17, 2004; 1 ACS, 1 EM, MS (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Played bass in Janet's band.
    - Traester, Mary C., February 23-August 18, 2004; 1 EM, 1 TL, 2 TLS (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - UR Vox, January 6, 2004; 1 ACS, 1 ALS (Box 2, Folder 24A)
    - W (miscellaneous), Date unknown; 1 Event (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Waldman, Anne, February 28, 2006; 1 ACS (Box 2, Folder 25A)
    - Weiss, Joanne, July 29, 1985-December 29, 1992; 3 ACS, 3 APCS, 1 TCS, 1 TL, 6 TLS (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Weissner, Carl, March 8, 1980-March 3, 1981; 1 ALS, 4 TLS (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Winokur, Neil and Anne Umland, April 9, 1973-March 20, 2005; 3 ACS, 2 APCS, 1 ALS, 9 Events, 2 TLS, 6 photographs (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Wolfe, Edward, March 8, 2004-March 13, 2006; 2 TLS (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Janet's former English professor and friend.
  - Subseries Ib: Publishing Correspondence, 13 ALS, 25 TLS, assorted material
    - A-G, Date unknown (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - H-Z, Date unknown (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Subseries Ic: Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, Date unknown; 8 ACS, 2 ALS, 8 APCS, 1 EM, 4 Events, MS, 11 Misc. (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Series II: Writings by Janet Hamill
  - Subseries IIa: Books
    - Body of Water, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      Proofs with corrections
    - Body of Water, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Bowery Books, related correspondence, publishing information, photographs, promotional material, guest book
    - The Enigma of Buster Keaton, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Self-published chapbook
    - Lost Ceilings, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Two copies of the manuscript
    - Lost Ceilings, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Emails, notebooks, photographs
    - Lost Ceilings, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Composition notebook, small journal
    - Nostaligia of the Infinite, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
      Correspondence, including Ocean View Books
    - Nostaligia of the Infinite, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4, 12)
      Art boards
    - Nostaligia of the Infinite, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Final proof
    - Nostaligia of the Infinite, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      MS drafts
    - Nostaligia of the Infinite, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7-10)
      Notes and notebooks
    - Nostaligia of the Infinite, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Book copies
    - Pleiades, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Self-published chapbook and front layout and artwork
    - The Temple, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 40-42)
      Telephone books, transcripts, manuscript pages, copies of manuscript, book mock-up, photographs, certificate of copyright registration
    - Troublante, written under Juan Hamill, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Letterpress printed in an edition of 100 by Oliphant Press
  - Subseries IIb: Broadsides
    - "The Big Sleep", written under Juan Hamill, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      2 copies of the broadside. 1 copy has the name “Juan” crossed out and replaced by “Janet.” Also included is the layout, with original artwork, for the broadside.
    - "Byron's Time Sheet", 2005 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Signed, no. 3 of 50
    - The Departure of the Argonauts, Date unknown (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Broadside and layout.
    - "From 'The Book of Marvels'", written under Juan Hamill, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      No. 47. Also included is the layout, with original artwork, for the broadside.
    - "Madame Bogart's Arts of Animal Ecstasy", written under Juan Hamill, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Signed, no. 99. Also included is the layout for the broadside.
    - "Mme. Bogart", written under Juan Hamill, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Also included is the layout, with original artwork, for the broadside.
    - "Requiem", 2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      No. 84
    - "Subterraneous", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      No. 102
    - "The Water Tower", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Subseries IIc: Avant
    - Avant, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      6 issues. Glassboro State College literary magazine. Both Patti (Patricia) Smith and Janet Hamill were on the Avant staff. It served as an early area over which the two bonded. Work by JH, but not PS, appears in several of these issues.
  - Subseries IId: Other Material
    - Other material, Date unknown (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
      Assorted poetry manuscripts, "Delouz Entago", drafts, "A Poem for All Seasons", handwritten lists.
    - Other material, Date unknown (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Subseries IIe: Other Publications
    - Publications, Date unknown (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Folder with assorted items, including: proofs for “The Birds of the Air” included in the Gary Indiana anthology Living with the Animals, also included is some correspondence with Indiana and the book’s editor; tear sheet from Kansas Quarterly; and items related to Janet's contribution to More Reflections on the Meaning of Life.
  - Subseries IIf: Other Material on Janet Hamill
    - Materials, Date unknown (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Assorted newspapers, writings and a student paper on JH.
- Series III: Announcements for Performances/Readings and Related Material
  - United Kingdom Trip, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 20-22)
    Assorted materials, including correspondence, books, brochures, receipts, and travel material related to Janet's trip to the UK to present a reading and workshop, also included is some correspondence related to Janet's UK trip to participate in the Latitude Festival.
  - Rubber Stamps, Date unknown (Box 3, Folder 23)
    3 rubber stamps used for flyers and announcement cards, including readings at The Poetry Project 1978? and a reading with Max Blagg at the Ear Inn.
  - Subject to Fits Reading, July 14 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    8 ½ x 14 inch poster for JH reading with Max Blagg at St. Marks Church. The poster has poems by both Blagg and JH. Also included is the layout, with original artwork by Kenneth Tisa.
  - Today's Radio reading, February 22, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    8 ½ by 14 inch poster for reading by Juan Hamill (JH’s nom de plume) at 41 Worth Street. The poster has a poem by JH. Also included is the layout, with original artwork by Kenneth Tisa.
  - Ear Inn reading with Ravi Singh, October 4 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Postcard, source material and layout for the postcard.
  - Short Pieces: Electric Music, Performance, Film, June 15, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    JH performed as “Janet H.” at 33 Grand Street. Other performers, included Laurie Anderson, Adele Bertei, Rhys Chatham, Glenn Branca, John Lurie, Jeffrey Lohn, and others.
  - Eggs over Dresden reading, January 9, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    2 9 x 14 inch posters for reading that also included Maxwell Blagg, David Matlin, and others. On the verso of one of the posters is a manuscript, with corrections, of JH poem “The Two Yellow Pills.”
  - The Arousing Word, November 7 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Small flyer for a reading that included Juan Hamill (JH’s nom de plume) at A.I.R. Gallery. Also included is the layout with original artwork for the flyer.
  - After 1980!, Mar 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Flyer and original artwork for JH reading with Adele Bertei and Max Blagg at the Mud[d Club].
  - Hudson Valley Poets Fest, August 13, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Flyer for the festival in which JH participated. There is also correspondence concerning a possible JH reading at the Strand Bookstore.
  - Walt Whitman Cultural Arts Center, April 18, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    2 flyers for JH and Moving Star’s performance as part of Whitman Sunday at the Walt Whitman Cultural Arts Center, Camden N.J. There is also some correspondence concerning the event.
  - People's Poetry Gathering, April 1, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Schedule and poster for the event, Mar 30–Apr 1, 2001. Patti Smith and her Band played with JH and Moving Star. The Gathering featured Stanley Kunitz, John Ashbery, Brenda Hillman, Galway Kinnell, and many others.
  - Oh My God! Festival, December 6, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
    JH participated in this Rededication of The Cathedral Church of Saint John the Devine. Folder includes invitation to the event, correspondence, stage pass, t-shirt, and other items. Other participants included, among many, Mike Albo, Samantha Jones, and Jayne Cortez.
  - Word: The Jay Liveson Memorial Poetry and Music Festival, June 8, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    JH participated in this festival presented by Exoterica and The College of Mount Saint Vincent (Bronx, N.Y). Folder includes flyer and card for the event, correspondence and program. Other participants included, among many, Billy Collins, Jim Carroll, Richard Hell, Edwin Torres, and Big Youth.
  - A Poet Paints: A One Woman Show, November 5-December 10, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Flyer, publicity photo, statement, checklist (with prices), and press coverage of JH solo exhibition of her paintings.
  - Cards and small items., Date unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Approximately 30 assorted items for JH readings and performances, including: participation in Stan Vanderbeek’s New Wilderness event “Dream Fest”, Sep 17, 1979; reading with Ed Friedman at the Zu; “All Hallow’s Eve” reading with Annabel Levitt at St. Mark’s Church; reading with Maureen Owen at the Ear Inn; reading with Jack Collom at St. Mark’s Church; reading (as Juan Hamill) with Barbara Kruger at Artists Space; and programs from The Poetry Project’s Annual New Year’s Day Marathon Reading.
  - 8 ½ x 11 inch items, Date unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Approximately 50 assorted items, primarily flyers and “set lists” for JH readings and performances, including: participation in “Greatest Hits 60 Poets: 60 Poems All-Star Benefit” for NYC Poetry Calendar at Environ; original artwork for flyer for “Ladies Choice” reading with Ann Powell and Ruth Kligman at 11 West 20; items related to participation in “Praise Day for Philip Lamatia! ‘Becoming Visible’”; readings 17 at the 9th Precinct Gallery, ABC NO RIO and the Figaro Cafe; and flyer and program for “Jet of Blood” directed by Bob Holman at Ward Nasse Gallery.
  - 8 ½ x 14 inch posters, Date unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
    8 items, including posters announcing: The Poetry Project Valentine’s Day Reading, 1988; Rose Drachler Memorial Reading, 1983, and “Poems at the 9th Precinct Gallery”.
  - Larger posters and programs, Date unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    15 items, including posters announcing: The Poets Theatre and The Poetry Project’s Annual New Year’s Day Marathon Reading. Programs include the program for “Patti Smith’s Meltdown,” London, 2005 at which JH also performed. Also: posters for “The Blank Generation and Beyond,” grand opening of the Pioneer Theater, New York.
  - The Poets Theatre and Kerouac posters, Date unknown (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Series IV: Photographs
  - Morocco polaroids, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    20 3 ¼ x 4 ¼ inch black and white Polaroid photographs taken by JH on her Moroccan trip.
  - Morocco photographs taken by Neil Winokur, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    6 black and white photographs, of assorted sizes, of Morocco and JH in Morocco. There are also copy negatives for one of the photographs and a contact sheet of the negatives.
  - Brion Gysin and Adele Bertei at the Nova Convention, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    8 x 10 inch black and white photograph by Marcia Resnick.
  - Sun Dance Pledgers–Cheyenne, Date unknown (Box 4, Folder 25)
    8 x 10 inch copy photograph from the Museum of Natural History.
  - Death Valley Landscapes, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    3 8 x 10 inch black and white photographs by Neil Winokur.